Bilibili has officially launched its own AI video creation platform, Updream.
UpDream.
Its biggest feature is the support for an infinite canvas.
Plus, it supports the Seedance 2.0 video generation model.
It also supports a variety of other AI video generation models.
like Kling 3.0,
and Alibaba's Wan 2.7.
We can add nodes just like we would in ComfyUI.
And then, by connecting these nodes, you can build a video generation workflow.
It allows you to call upon different skills, or even create your own.
Plus, it supports long-term memory.
So in this video, we're going to put UpDream to the test in a variety of scenarios to really see what it can do.
UpDream.
So, how good is its video creation capability, really?
Before we start the tests,
First, let me show you a few examples I've generated with Updream.
Let's see what Updream can do.
For this video, I started with this image that I generated using AI.
And this image is of a skincare product.
And then, I had Updream generate a video for this skincare product based on that image.
Let's play it first.
Let's see how it turned out.
As you can see, the result is quite impressive.
Whether it's the scene itself or the sound and music accompanying it,
or the movements of the characters in the scene.
and even the effect of the skincare product itself.
Everything looks incredibly realistic.
Alright, let's see what else it can do.
And this is what I had it generate.
a clip that looks like it's from a video game.
As you can see in this scene,
Plus, the character animations and effects are all incredibly well done.
And here, I also had it generate a...
This is a clip from a modern urban drama.
This is just a short clip.
Let's play it.
You've been watching for a while now.
I'm just waiting for a reply. Just waiting for a reply.
And the effect is pretty impressive, too.
And it's not just about generating short video clips with UpDream.
We can also use its infinite canvas and workflow functions
to generate more complete
and more cohesive long-form videos.
Here's a test I ran of a spaceship landing on Mars.
This video shows some scientists conducting an expedition on Mars.
And now, let's take a look at the full video, clip by clip.
Let's start by playing the first one.
This is the scene of the spaceship landing.
As you can see, both the visuals and the audio are really impressive.
Now, let's take a look at the second clip.
Here, we get a full view of the spaceship.
Now, let's take a look at the third clip.
Here, the hatch of the spaceship opens.
And now for the next clip.
Here, the astronaut is stepping out of the spacecraft. Surface contact confirmed.
Now, let's look at this scene.
And here's the second astronaut, stepping out of the spacecraft.
Then, they place down the instrument.
And let's see what happens next.
Here, the Mars rover is deploying from the spacecraft.
Alright, let's keep watching.
And here, the drone begins its survey.
And now, let's take a look at the final clip.
Here, the astronaut begins to explore Mars.
Plus, UpDream's infinite canvas and workflow features...
We can also build even more complex workflows.
For example, here we can provide an image.
And then, through a video node,
and have it combine the image with the previous video.
to generate even more complex scenes.
For example, take this scene I generated earlier.
Explorers discover an ancient spaceship in the desert.
And the scientific team excavated the spaceship.
and then they entered the ship.
So, let's take a quick look at the video it generated.
Alright, so for the first scene...
After the storm, a crack appears in the desert.
And inside, a spaceship is discovered.
In the second scene, the explorer personally discovers the spaceship.
In the third scene, we see the explorer...
reports the discovery of the spacecraft.
This is Miller. I've found something under the sand.
It's not rock.
It's not a meteorite.
It looks artificial.
Let's see what happens next.
And this is where the researchers began their excavation.
Once we're sure everything under the sand is a blurred seal,
Everything under the sand is a blurred seal.
Next scene.
So, the team began discussing the geological age of the spacecraft.
This type of alloy shouldn't be in this stratum.
The sedimentation period is nearly a million years.
The next scene shows them excavating the spaceship.
Oh my god, this isn't a building.
This is a spaceship.
And in the next scene, everyone boards the spaceship.
Oh my god, that's not a building.
And the next scene takes us inside the spaceship.
A spaceship this advanced... there's no way this is human technology.
And the next scene is a holographic projection inside the spaceship.
That's Mars.
Impossible. Mars was never supposed to be green.
Mars was never supposed to be green.
Originally, I was going to generate a more complete sci-fi short film.
But due to time constraints,
So, I've only generated a few clips here.
So, I didn't end up generating the final, full-length video.
So, from these examples we've seen,
So, I'm sure you can all get a feel for it.
UpDream's capabilities in video creation are actually pretty impressive.
Alright, let's dive into some more detailed tests.
If this video gets over a thousand likes,
I'll be bringing you more in the future.
and advanced AI video generation techniques.
Alright, first, let's head over to Updream.
And right here, you'll see the content input box.
Inside this input box,
and we can just type in our creative ideas or concepts.
You can also type a forward slash in the input box to bring up the corresponding skills.
And down here, you'll find all these official options as well.
For the skills, we can click 'View All' to see everything.
As you can see,
The platform officially provides a ton of skills here.
And then, we can also go over to the workspace here.
to create our own skills.
And for the skills provided by the platform,
All we have to do is click, and then click 'Activate Now'.
And we can start using the official skills right away.
Now, let's dive into some more in-depth testing.
We're going to be testing this out on Updream's infinite canvas.
From here, we can click to create a new project.
And this whole area here is the canvas.
And over on the right, we have this dialogue box.
And over here, we can go ahead and hide this.
And then we can test it directly on the canvas.
Then, we'll right-click the mouse.
Here, we can add an image node.
Click 'Add'.
We can have it generate an image for us.
Then, we'll click the dropdown.
and you'll see it supports a variety of image generation models.
including Nano Banana Pro and Nano Banana 2.
and Nano Banana 2.
And Seedream 5.0.
And here, we can select Seedream 5.0.
You can also select the image's aspect ratio here.
For example, we can choose a 3:2 ratio.
The prompt I'm using is 'premium skincare product packaging'.
And then, hit send.
and have it generate an image of a skincare product's packaging for us.
And there we have it, the generation is complete.
Alright, let's create another node.
and have it generate a video from this image.
We can just drag this plus sign.
And right here, we can click on this dropdown option.
to select the mode.
So, for this one, we'll select the video generation mode.
And for this one, we'll select image-to-video.
And for the model, we can just select Seedance 2.0.
For the aspect ratio...
We'll just stick with the default 16:9 here.
For the quality, I'll just stick with the default, 720p.
Plus, it also supports 1080p, 2K, and even 4K.
Then, we'll input the prompt.
and have it reference the skincare product packaging from image one.
Generate an 8-second, high-end beauty product showcase video.
This includes soft, natural lighting on the product as it sits on a table.
Then, a hand opens the bottle cap.
And it even specifies the sound requirements here.
This includes the sound of the cap opening.
the sound of fingers rubbing it in,
and some quiet, high-end background music.
And then we can just hit 'send'.
And right here, you can see the workflow starting to run.
It will then use this image as a reference to generate the corresponding video.
Alright, the generation is complete.
Alright, let's play it back.
Let's see the result.
Lightweight, moisturizing, and it absorbs smoothly. The result it generated is really impressive.
Whether it's the background music or all these little details,
Even the hand movements as it's being applied look incredibly realistic.
It's hard to tell that it was AI-generated.
Here, we can drag this plus sign again.
And right here in the mode section below,
So, we'll just select 'Video Generation'.
And the default setting here is 'All-in-One Reference'.
It will use our previous video as a reference.
And here's the prompt I'm using.
Let's keep going and generate a scene of a real person holding a skincare product, showcasing it from the front.
And then, hit send.
Now, let's have it generate the second clip.
And it's done.
Let's hit play. Lightweight hydration, gently absorbed.
Its gentle formula is suitable for all skin types. And this result is really impressive.
And it connects seamlessly with the last clip.
Alright, next up, let's test out its performance with multiple characters interacting.
So, let's go ahead and add a video generation node.
And then, we'll enter the prompt.
The prompt I entered was for 4 original characters.
performing different actions simultaneously in a restaurant.
One person is serving food.
one is pulling out a chair,
One person is looking down at the menu.
One person raises a hand to signal the waiter.
The camera pans slowly.
And the positions of all four characters remain clear.
The audio includes the sounds of cutlery, ambient noise, and natural dialogue.
Now, let's take a look at this more complex, multi-subject interaction.
So, how does it actually turn out?
Alright, it's done generating.
Let's play it and see how it turned out.
Hmm.
This looks pretty good.
Hello.
Hello, could I get another glass of water, please?
As you can see, it's generated this scene with multiple characters.
The results are actually quite impressive.
Plus, each character in the video is distinct.
Their voices and actions are all distinct as well.
This video follows our prompt almost perfectly.
one person serving food,
one person pulling out a chair,
one person looking at the menu,
and specific details like one person raising their hand to signal the waiter.
It followed our prompts almost perfectly.
Alright, let's continue with our testing.
Let's add a video node again.
Alright, for this test, let's see how well it can render the texture of objects.
So, I'll just type in the prompt here.
Generate an 8-second, first-person ASMR video of a real object.
The shot is an extreme close-up.
a pair of clean hands,
Cutting a piece of freshly baked puff pastry on a wooden table.
The prompt asks for a small knife to gently press against the surface of the puff pastry.
The flaky pastry cracks ever so slightly.
Then, the pastry is slowly sliced open.
The steam from the inside and the soft filling are revealed as a small piece of the pastry is lifted by a fork.
The flaky pastry crumbs fall onto the plate.
The sound effects here should include the sound of the flaky pastry crumbling.
The soft clink of the knife against the plate, the faint sound of steam...
Alright, the video generation is complete.
Let's play it and see how it turned out.
And from this angle, you get the first-person sound of the knife cutting through the puff pastry.
And the sound of the fork hitting the plate, it's all just perfect.
It followed our prompt almost perfectly.
And the way it recreates all these details is pretty impressive, too.
Especially after the pastry is cut open,
and the steam coming out from inside.
The level of detail here is just incredible.
Alright, let's take a look at some of the other scenarios I tested.
So, for this one, I had it generate a game scene. Let's take a look at the prompt here.
The prompt here was to generate an 8-second video showcasing an original game character's skill.
An original ice mage, standing in the center of a circular arena.
wearing a silver-white robe.
holding a transparent crystal staff.
And a blue magic circle appears on the ground.
A chill spreads across the ground.
He raises his staff.
The magic circle on the ground begins to glow.
Blue ice crystals rise from the edges of the magic circle.
Then, the mage swings his staff.
The ice wall shatters into countless blades.
The camera freezes on the character's finishing pose.
Let's hit play.
The game footage it generated is also absolutely perfect.
Then, I also tested its ability to generate...
a first-person, original horror exploration game scene.
The player, holding a flashlight, walks into a corridor of an abandoned Mars research station.
The walls have peeling metal plates, and other details like that.
The first-person view slowly moves forward.
The flashlight illuminates the floor of the corridor.
The camera pans to a half-open hatch on the left.
Slight tremor.
The flashlight beam reveals scratch marks on the wall.
And a name tag, dropped on the floor.
A sound of metal clashing echoes from a distance.
The camera stops abruptly.
And here are the sound effects it generated.
This includes breathing sounds, the faint buzz of a flashlight, and so on.
And now, let's hit play.
And you can clearly hear the breathing in the video.
And the sounds of the metal, too.
And all the specific details we asked for,
And it generated pretty much all of them.
And even these scratches on the wall.
Alright, let's crank up the difficulty.
Alright, for this next one, I've got two images of anime scenes ready.
I've also got an image of a four-panel comic storyboard.
We'll have Updream use this 4-panel storyboard as a reference to generate the corresponding video.
Let's test how well Updream understands storyboards.
and its understanding of 2D composition.
Then, we'll upload these three images.
First, let's have it reference this four-panel comic storyboard.
And also reference the original female lead's appearance and the original male lead's appearance.
Generate an anime short film.
And we'll have it generate the video strictly following the sequence of these panels.
Alright, it's done. Let's play it and see how it turned out.
The result is actually pretty decent.
Plus, they're even having a conversation in Japanese.
So, it's basically recreated the four panels we asked for. And after some pretty thorough testing, the scenes came out great.
So, as you can see, Updream's performance is truly impressive.
Especially its infinite canvas and workflow setup.
we can build even more complex scenes.
to create even more perfect videos. But due to time constraints,
So, we're not going to run any more tests here.
And that's all for this video.
Please feel free to like, subscribe, and share.
Thanks for watching.